501, Panache-B, Datta Mandir Road, Wakad, Pune, Maharashtra, India, 411057

🛘 (+91) 9975258323 | 🗷 vaibhavbhavsar62@gmail.com | 🐔 vaibhav6233m.github.io | 🖸 vaibhav6233m | 🖹 vaibhav-bhavsar | 🛅

vaibhav-bhavsar-000bb276 | S live:vaibhav6233m

"A bug is never just a mistake. It represents something bigger. An error of thinking that makes you who you are."

# **Summary**

Software Engineer with 5 years experience specializing in backend, frontend UI, and Cross-platform desktop application development. Possess comprehensive knowledge of JavaScript concepts with solid Understanding of asynchronous programming. Super nerd who loves Linux and macOS and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

# Technical Proficiency \_\_\_\_\_

**Programming Languages** JavaScript, Node.JS, Python

Web Technologies VueJs, ReactJs, MaterialUI, HTML5, CSS3

**Frameworks** ElectronJs, ExpressJs

Databases MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Servers Apache2, Nginx, IIS

**Version Control** Git

**Operating Systems** Linux, Mac, Windows

**Cloud Tech's** Amazon Web Services, Google Firebase, Docker Containerization, Travis Cl

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

CALSOFT INC. Pune, India

### SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

July. 2019 - PRESENT

- Developing frontend applications using **Vue.js** framework as per client's requirements
- Producing clean, efficient code based on specifications
- · Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Integrate software components and third-party programs
- Estimated work hours and tracked progress using Scrum methodology.
- Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies

## WINJIT TECHNOLOGIES PVT. LTD.

Nashik, India Dec. 2017 - Jun. 2019

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER & FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Code, test and operate Node.js based services
- Build customer-facing UI and back-end services
- · Define code architecture decisions to support a high-performance and scalable product
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade existing software
- Recommend improvements to existing software programs as necessary
- · Optimize applications for maximum speed and scalability
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- · Responsible for the dealing with problems, defect, fixing and troubleshooting

### SUPER SIMPLE SOFTWARE LLP.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashik, India

Aug. 2015 - Nov. 2017

• Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications

- Develop and implement new ERP software programs in Python/XML based framework
- Testing and deploying programs and systems
- Work with developers to design algorithms and flowcharts
- Create technical documentation for reference and reporting
- Maintain and improve the performance of existing software
- Fixing and improving existing software
- · Collaborate well with engineers to design and create advanced, elegant and efficient systems
- · Gather and evaluate user feedback

# **Education**

#### SINHGAD COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING

**BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY** 

Score: 62.60%

Pune, Maharashtra May. 2011 - Jun. 2015

# **Projects Handled**

### **Seagate: Cloud Storage Manager**

seagate.com

Duration: Ongoing project

FRONT-END DEVELOPER · Team Size: 13+

- Description: Cloud Storage Manager (CSM) is a virtualization layer that provides functionality to configure and provision storage, manage users, set policies and provide statistics.
- · Responsibilities:
  - Understanding the business requirements and developing customer-facing UI VueJs Framework.
  - Interaction with development teams to integrate code.
  - Implementing reusable UI-components as per **UI-styleguide**.
  - Estimated work hours and tracked progress using **Scrum** methodology.

#### **BuildingLink: Online Residential Property Management Software**

buildinglink.com

Duration: 4 Months

FRONT-END DEVELOPER · Team Size: 4

- **Description:** BuildingLink.com is a property management software developed to help property managers handle their operations better.
- Responsibilities:
  - Understanding the business requirements and developing customer-facing UI **VueJs** Framework.
  - Interaction with development teams to integrate code.
  - Implemented reusable UI-components with Material-UI for BuildingLink web application.

#### **lagon: Decentralized and Secure Cloud Platform**

iagon.com

Duration: 12 Months

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

· Team Size: 5

- Description: IAGON is an Open Source platform for harnessing the storage capacities and processing power of multiple computers over a decentralized Blockchain grid.
- · Responsibilities:
  - Lead in the development and implementation of distributed storage using **BitTorrent** technology and processing functionality using IPFS (Distributed Web) and **Docker** containers in lagon Cloud Services.
  - Implementation and Integration of Iagon Cloud Services in a Cross-platform desktop application using ElectronJs and ReactJs.
  - Developed Peer-2-Peer communication system to achieve decentralize processing functionality.
  - Development and consumption of **NodeJs** APIs with **ExpressJs**.
  - Integrated an HTTP tunneling service to resolve the node communication issues of NAT/Firewall.
  - Developed overall application with **ES6** standards for better usages of javascript modules.

#### Morpheus. Network: Blockchain Powered Global Supply

morpheus.network

Duration: 1 Month

- SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · Team Size: 5
- **Description:** Morpheus. Network is a full-service, global, automated, supply chain platform with an integrated cryptocurrency payment system utilizing blockchain technology.
- · Responsibilities:
  - Collaborate with the rest of the engineering team to design and launch new features.
  - Implemented distributed document storage functionality based on IPFS (Distributed Web).
  - Responsible for the dealing with problems, defect fixing and troubleshooting.

#### **HashMicro: ERP Solution Provider**

hashmicro.com

PYTHON DEVELOPER

Duration: 3 Months Team Size: 3

- Description: HashMicro is a Singapore's leading Cloud ERP & CRM vendor, offering innovative business software solutions and services customized for various industries.
- Responsibilities:
  - Collaborate with the rest of the engineering team to design and launch new features.
  - Developed numerous web applications based on **Odoo** (Open Source ERP framework) in Python and guaranteed that they exceeded the expectations of our clients.

## **Honors & Awards**

2019 1st Place, Technical Treasure Hunt Calsoft Inc.

2018 Key Contributor, World of Winjit (WOW)

Best Project - IAGON, World of Winjit (WOW) Winjit Tech. 2018

Winjit Tech.